A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, 55th Street, Series 16 FA362
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, 55th Street, Series 16
1968-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Cannon, James M.
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
Ronan, William J. (William John)
Whitman, Ann
New York (State). Dept. of Civil Service
Morrow, Hugh
New York (State). State Commission for Human Rights
Boyd, Joseph H.
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
FA362
40 Box(es)
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 16
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Arrangement note
This series is divided into 6 subseries:
Subseries 1 - Trips, 1973-1974 Subseries 2 - Schedules, 1969-1975 Subseries 3 - Correspondence Files, 1968-1974 Subseries 4 - Letters of Support Regarding the Vice Presidential Nomination, 1974 Subseries 5 - Subject Files of Kathy Huldrum and Nancy Towell, 1970-1974 Subseries 6 - Invitations, 1972-1974
Scope and Contents note
NOTE TO RESEARCHERS
This series contains the office files of Ann Whitman, Nancy Towell, and Kathy Huldrum. They document the official activities of these individuals in the execution of their duties as members of Nelson A. Rockefeller's gubernatorial and personal staffs. The actions, decisions, and exchanges of information or points of view documented here occurred in the course of proposing and implementing policies for the Rockefeller administration, political campaigns, and/or Rockefeller's personal activities. However, unless a document is specifically addressed to or from Nelson A. Rockefeller, or is referred to in a document addressed to him, it should not be assumed that he saw the document or was aware of its existence or substance. Furthermore, researchers should bear in mind that staff files may contain documents or drafts addressed to Rockefeller that were never shown to him.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This series documents portions of Nelson A. Rockefeller's public and private activities between 1968 and 1974. These records were created and maintained by members of Rockefeller's staff at his office at 22 West 55th Street, New York, also called the New York Office. Rockefeller was one of the first New York governors to maintain a permanent office in New York City. In general, Rockefeller was in Albany only while the Legislature was in session or for special occasions. The management of his public duties was undertaken largely at 55th Street. The office was paid for privately by Rockefeller, but many of the staff were public employees. When he resigned as governor, on December 20, 1973, some of the staff became Rockefeller's personal employees. Some of them went on the federal payroll and moved to Washington, DC, when Rockefeller became Vice President of the United States on December 19, 1974.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)
Arms control; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Human rights; Civil service; Civil defense -- United States; Civil defense; Arms control -- United States; Government policy; Federal government -- United States; Economics; Civil service -- New York (State); Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Presidential campaigns -- United States; Political science; New York (N.Y.); Legislation -- New York (State); Political campaigns -- United States; New York (State); International relations; International economic relations; Latin America; International relations -- United States; Public policy; Public relations; State governments -- United States; United States; Vice-Presidents -- United States; Cannon, James M.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Ronan, William J. (William John); Whitman, Ann; New York (State). Dept. of Civil Service; Morrow, Hugh; New York (State). State Commission for Human Rights; Boyd, Joseph H.; New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
- Trips, 1973-1974; 1
  Arrangement note
  The subseries is arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents note
  This subseries documents Rockefeller's trips around the country after leaving the governorship and before becoming Vice President. There is a separate file for each trip. The documentation includes correspondence, interoffice memoranda, and itineraries regarding the trip and the event that he was attending. Rockefeller was invited to speak at most of the events; some files include transcripts of his speech or remarks.
  - Illinois, September 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Trip to Chicago to speak. Thank you letters.
  - Ohio, October 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Trip to Cleveland. Thank you letters.
  - Michigan, October 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Trip for Lincoln Day Dinner. Thank you letters. Clippings from the trip.
  - Arizona, October 25, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Thank you letters written to people in Arizona. Newspaper clippings covering the visit.
  - Arizona, October 25, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    NAR's folder for Arizona trip.
  - Iowa, October 30, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Trip to Des Moines for Iowa Republican Party Dinner. Thank you letters.
  - Iowa, October 30, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    NAR's folder for Iowa trip.
  - North Dakota, November 26, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Trip to Grand Forks to speak. Thank you letters.
  - Colorado, January 31, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Transcripts of press conference and interview with NAR. Thank you letters.
  - Illinois, February 8, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Trip to Rockford to honor Congressman John B. Anderson. Thank you letters. Newspaper clippings. Transcripts of NAR's remarks and interviews.
  - Illinois, February 8, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    NAR's folders for Illinois trip.
  - Illinois, February 8, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minnesota, February 12, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Trip to Minneapolis. Transcript of press conference.
  - South Dakota, February 12, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Trip for Republican fund raiser. Transcripts of press conference and speech. Thank you letters. Clippings regarding event.
  - South Dakota, February 12, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    NAR's folder for South Dakota trip.
  - Kansas, February 13, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Trip to Topeka in support of Bob Dole. Thank you letters. Transcript of remarks by NAR.
  - Kansas, February 13, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    NAR's folder for Kansas trip.
  - Texas, February 21, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Trip to Dallas for Dinner of Dallas Council of World Affairs. Thank you letters. Transcripts of speech and other remarks made by NAR.
  - Montana, February 28, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Trip to Billings for a Republican fund raiser. Thank you letters. Transcripts of interview and press conference.
  - Montana, February 28, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Hugh Morrow's folder for Montana trip.
  - Oregon, March 1, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Trip to Seaside for the Dorchester Conference. Thank you letters. Transcripts of TV taping, press conference, and the speech made by NAR.
  - Oregon, March 1, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Hugh Morrow's folder for Oregon trip.
  - Pennsylvania, March 7, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Trip to Philadelphia for Republican dinner. Thank you letters. Transcripts of remarks and press conference of NAR.
  - Pennsylvania, March 7, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    NAR's folder for Pennsylvania trip.
  - Florida, March 8, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Trip to Sarasota for a Lincoln Day Rally and Dinner. Thank you letters. Transcripts of remarks by NAR at the dinner. Clippings from newspapers detailing visit.
  - Florida, March 8, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    NAR's folder for Florida trip.
  - Massachusetts, March 13, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Trip to Boston. Thank you letters. Transcripts of remarks and press conference by NAR.
  - Massachusetts, March 13, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    NAR's folder for Massachusetts trip.
  - Illinois, March 30, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Trip to Chicago for the Midwest Republican Leadership Conference. Transcripts of newspaper clippings about Republican governors. Thank you letters. Transcript of remarks by NAR.
  - Florida, April 3, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Trip to Miami. Clippings detailing event. Remarks by NAR. Thank you letters.
  - Nebraska, April 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Trip to Lincoln. Thank you letters. Remarks by NAR at luncheon.
  - Nebraska, April 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    NAR's folder for Nebraska trip.
  - Missouri, May 9, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Trip to Kansas City. Thank you letters. Remarks of NAR. Internal memoranda from George Hinman regarding people to recognize.
  - Arkansas, May 10, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Trip to honor NAR's brother, Winthrop, who was Governor of Arkansas. Thank you letters. Newspaper, "Arkansas Outlook," about the Republican party in Arkansas, covering visit.
  - Arkansas, May 10, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    NAR's folders for Arkansas trip.
  - Arkansas, May 10, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Michigan, May 22, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Trip to Lansing for Republican fund raiser. Thank you letters. Remarks of NAR. Internal memoranda.
  - Michigan, May 22, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    NAR's folders for Michigan trip.
  - Michigan, May 22, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Ohio, June 14, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Trip to Cleveland. Thank you letters. Copy of "Ohio Republican News" with coverage of NAR visit within.
  - Ohio, June 14, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    NAR's folder for Ohio trip.
  - Wyoming, June 18, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Trip to Gillette. Thank you letters. Remarks and press conference by NAR. Transcript of speech.
  - Wyoming, June 18, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    NAR's folder for Wyoming trip.
  - Washington, June 19, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Trip for Republican party fund raisers. Thank you letters. Transcript of speech delivered by NAR.
  - Washington, June 19, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    NAR's folder for Washington trip.
  - Maine, August 9, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Trip to Bangor for Maine Republican Finance Committee Dinner. Thank you letters. Transcript of remarks by NAR.
  - Maine, August 9, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    NAR's folder for Maine trip.
  - Illinois, August 11, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    NAR's folders for Republican Governors Conference held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - Illinois, August 11, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Rhode Island, September 1974 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    Trip to Warwick. Thank you letters.
  - Utah, October 2, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Trip to Provo to speak at Brigham Young University. Thank you letters.
  - California, October 3, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Thank you letters.
- Schedules, 1969-1975; 2
  This subseries consists of Rockefeller's daily itineraries, as maintained by Nancy Towell. Some files contain correspondence and interoffice memoranda regarding specific events. Copies of the schedules, printed on pink paper, were distributed to Rockefeller's advance staff and other staff members responsible for arranging and overseeing the logistics of his travels.
  - November 1969 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - December 1969 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Monthly Calendars 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Block schedules for the entire month used to plan out the Governor's schedule.
  - March 1970 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - April 1970 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - May 1970 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - June 1970 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - July 1970 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - August 1970 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - September 1970 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - October 1970 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - November 1970 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - December 1970 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - January 1971 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - February 1971 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - March 1971 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - April 1971 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - May 1971 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - June 1971 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - July 1971 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - August 1971 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - September 1971 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - October 1971 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - November 1971 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - December 1971 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - January 1972 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - February 1972 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - March 1972 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - April 1972 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - May 1972 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - June 1972 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - July 1972 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - August 1972 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - September 1972 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - October 1972 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - November 1972 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - December 1972 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - January 1973 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - February 1973 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - March 1973 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - April 1973 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - May 1973 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - June 1973 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - July 1973 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - August 1973 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - September 1973 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - October 1973 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - November 1973 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - December 1973 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - January 1974 (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - February 1974 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - March 1974 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - April 1974 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - May 1974 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - June 1974 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - July 1974 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - August 1974 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - September 1974 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - October 1974 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - December 1974 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - August 26/27, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - September 12/13, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 114)
- Correspondence Files, 1968-1974; 3
  There is a separate file for each year; the correspondence is arranged alphabetically thereunder.
  These files were maintained by Ann Whitman, Rockefeller's executive secretary. It consists mostly of outgoing correspondence, although there are some incoming letters. The correspondence is with heads of state, American political figures, and private citizens. The correspondence covers a broad range of issues and reflects Rockefeller's policy of giving each letter writer a proper response. At the end of the subseries are two folders of letters to John Mitchell, Attorney General of the United States, and John Ehrlichman, Counsel to President Richard M. Nixon. There is no indication as to why this correspondence is segregated.
  - G, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    NAR to Jack Gilhooley, head of the MTA, September 5, 1968.
  - Nixon: NAR's Acceptance to Lead President Nixon's Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    NAR to President Richard M. Nixon expressing NAR's interest in undertaking the Presidential Mission to Latin America, February 12, 1969.
  - A, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - B, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Birthday Acknowledgements, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - C, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - D, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - E, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - F, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - G, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Governor's Conference Acknowledgements, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - H, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - I-J, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 127)
  - K, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 128)
  - L, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 129)
  - M, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 130)
  - N, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 131)
  - O, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - P-Q, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - R, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - S, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - T, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - U-V, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - W, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - X-Y-Z, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 139)
  - A, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 140)
  - B, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - C, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - D, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - E, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - F, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 145)
  - G, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 146)
  - Governor's Conference Acknowledgements, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 147)
  - H, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - I-J, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - K, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 150)
  - L, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - M, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - N, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - O, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 154)
  - P-Q, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - R, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - S, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 157)
  - T, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 158)
  - U-V, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 159)
  - W, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 160)
  - Y-Z, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 161)
  - A, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 162)
  - B, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - Birthday Acknowledgements, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 164)
  - C, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 165)
  - D, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 166)
  - E, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 167)
  - F, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 168)
  - G, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - H, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 170)
  - I-J, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 171)
  - K, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 172)
  - L, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 173)
  - M, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 174)
  - N, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 175)
  - O, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 176)
  - P-Q, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 177)
  - R, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 178)
  - S, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 179)
  - T, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - U-V, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - W, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - Y-Z, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - A, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 184)
  - B, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 185)
  - C, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 186)
  - D, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 187)
  - E, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 188)
  - F, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 189)
  - G, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 190)
  - H, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 191)
  - I-J, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 192)
  - K, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 193)
  - L, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 194)
  - M, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 195)
  - N, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 196)
  - O, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 197)
  - P-Q, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 198)
  - R, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 199)
  - S, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 200)
  - T, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 201)
  - U-V, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 202)
  - W, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 203)
  - Y-Z, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 204)
  - B, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 205)
  - C, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 206)
  - D, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 207)
  - E, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 208)
  - F, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 209)
  - G, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 210)
  - H, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 211)
  - I-J, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 212)
  - K, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 213)
  - L, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 214)
  - M, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 215)
  - N, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 216)
  - O, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 217)
  - P-Q, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 218)
  - R, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 219)
  - S, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 220)
  - T, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 221)
  - U-V, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 222)
  - W, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 223)
  - Y-Z, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 224)
  - Correspondence with John Ehrlichman, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 225)
    NAR letters to John Ehrlichman, Counsel to President Richard M. Nixon.
  - Correspondence with John Mitchell, 1970-1972 (Box 15, Folder 226)
    NAR letters to John Mitchell, Attorney General of the United States.
- Letters of Support Regarding the Vice Presidential Nomination, 1974; 4
  This series is arranged alphabetically by name.
  Following President Gerald R. Ford's nomination of Nelson Rockefeller to fill the vacant vice presidency, many private citizens and public officials sent Rockefeller letters of congratulation and support. The correspondence came after the announcement of the selection, during the lengthy confirmation hearings, and upon Rockefeller's swearing-in on December 19, 1974. Some of those letters are here; however, the subseries consists primarily of carbon copies of Rockefeller's acknowledgements.
  - A, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 227)
  - C, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 228)
  - D, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 229)
  - E, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 230)
  - F, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 231)
  - G, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 232)
  - H, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 233)
  - I-J, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 234)
  - K, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 235)
  - L, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 236)
  - Ma-Me, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 237)
  - Mi-My, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 238)
  - N, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 239)
  - N, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 240)
  - P-Q, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 241)
  - R, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 242)
  - Sa-Sl, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 243)
  - Sm-Sw, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 244)
  - T, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 245)
  - U-V, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 246)
  - W, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 247)
  - Y-Z, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 248)
- Subject Files of Kathy Huldrum and Nancy Towell, 1970-1974; 5
  Kathy Huldrum and Nancy Towell were assistants to Ann Whitman, Rockefeller's executive secretary. Subjects include Rockefeller's 1970 gubernatorial reelection campaign; the 1973 Republican Governor's Conference, hosted by Rockefeller; the National Commission on Water Quality, chaired by Rockefeller; and preparations for the vice presidential confirmation hearings. There is also a large amount of material regarding the Commission on Critical Choices for Americans, a private study project on national public policy initiated and chaired by Rockefeller, and "The Modern State in a Changing World," a New York State-funded study project that preceded and inspired the Critical Choices Commission.
  - Advance Office - Materials, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 249)
    Forms and memoranda regarding the proper protocol involved in scheduling events for the Governor. Includes mention of George Pataki, later Governor of New York, who began his political career on NAR's advance staff.
  - Advance Office - Thank You Form Letters, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 250)
    Standard form letters used by the staff to thank individuals for their assistance with an appearance by NAR.
  - Advance Office - Thank You Letters/Procedures, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 251)
    Forms to list those individuals who were to receive thank you letters; memoranda regarding the proper procedures in handling events for the Governor.
  - Art Auction Materials, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 252)